为什么今天这么多人死呢？
Why are there so many people died today?
(Luk: The 8319th night)
陆仔，吃饭啦
Luk, dinner is ready
来啦
Coming
趁热呀
Hurry
画完这一点点
AImost done
一分钟
Give me a minute
One minute
喂
Hello?
是
Yes
是…我是…
Yes… Speaking…
明天下午？
Tomorrow afternoon?
是，行…没问题…
Yes, okay… no problem…
是，明白…
Yes, I got it…
那我明天…带所有作品上漫画社
Then I'll bring all my works  to your comic books company
请问你们的地址是哪里？
May I have your address please?
是，IFC(国际金融中心)
Yes, IFC. (International Finance Centre)
是…知道…
Yes, I got it…
观塘IFC？
IFC in Kwun Tong?
也知道…
Okay…
1804室…至1808室
Room 1804 to Room 1808
是，就用1806…那道门，好
Yes, use the door at 1806, okay
是，清楚，完全…
I totally got it…
谢谢…
Thanks…
(Dinner is ready.)
(Give me a minute.)
朱莉亚
Julia
糟啦
Shit!
麻烦了
Damn!
真是麻烦了
I've a problem
喂，朱莉亚
Hi, Julia?
就是嘛，我见抽屉里
只剩下一对胸罩内裤
Well, there's only one set of  lingerie left in the dresser
不知道是不是昨晚有个变态的
Wonder if there's a sex maniac
趁我们睡着摸进来偷走…
broke in last night and stole them…
偷剩一对呢
except for this set?
还是我喜欢的那对
Fortunately, this is the set I like most
不行，朱莉亚不喜欢我这么轻佻
No way, Julia doesn't  like me being frivolous
朱莉亚，耽误你几分钟行吗？
Julia, could you spare me a few minutes?
是呀，很抱歉
I sincerely apologize to you
昨天晚上我错过了我们的大日子
Yesterday I missed our big day
可是今天是我非常重要的日子嘛
because today is so important to me
今天这个日子会改变我的事业
Today will bring change to my career…
改变我的命运
Today will bring change to my fate
行呀，就这样
Sounds good, that's it
喂
Hello?
朱…朱莉亚
Ju… Julia
对不起
Sorry
我在搬家，搬好了打电话给你
I'm moving, I'll call you once settled
你也该准备好去见出版社
You better get ready  to go to the publisher
你怎知道我要去见出版社？
How do you know that?
听到些，猜到些
I overheard a little and I guessed so
你老是这样子，憋着胃气
You stilI have stomach gas
记得要吃东西，才好见人
You better eat before you go
胃气向上冲，你就打噎
Stomach gas goes up, you burp
向下挤就…两样都不好
Stomach gas goes down, you fart.  Both are not nice
这里信号很差，迟些打给你，再见
The reception here is bad.  I'll call you later, bye
棉花鸡
Spongy Chicken
来一笼…
One please…
好…请等一下
Okay, just a sec
小心烫…
Be careful… it's hot
谢谢
Thanks
喂，这是我的     不好意思
Hey, that's mine!       Sorry
这张才是我的
好…谢谢
That one is mine.       Okay… thanks
棉花鸡挺不错呢     是呀
The spongy chicken is good.       Yes
大婶，来一碟
Waiter, one please
来…小心烫
Okay… be careful, it's really hot
麻烦给我单子
Bill please
谢谢
Thanks
那鱼肚挺好吃
The fish maw is delicious
所以说你，整天游手好闲
You've been fooling around
平时又不多读几本书
putting no effort in educating yourself
这儿哪有鱼肚给你吃，那么珍贵？
Fish maws are so expensive,  how could they serve them here?
那是猪皮来的
That's just pig's skin
猪皮来的？
Pig's skin?
吃棉花鸡是为了那块火腿
I order Spongy Chicken for the ham
吃火腿？
Ham?
你不如去隔壁茶餐厅吃个火腿扒吧
Then why don't you go to a steak house  and order ham steak instead?
来茶楼，点一碟棉花鸡
You've come to a tea house  to order spongy chicken
就为了吃块火腿？
just for the ham?
我叫你不吃别的吗？
Did I tell you not to eat the side dish?
我是叫你先吃火腿
I'm just telling you to eat the ham first
说这么久，都不领会我的意思
You stilI don't get it
那棉花鸡的馅，很明显是昨夜剩菜
The stuffing of spongy chicken  is leftovers from yesterday
鱼肚是猪皮
The maw is just pig's skin
吃火腿最实在了
The ham is the most precious ingredient
是不是，小子？     是的…
Is that right, kid?       Yes…
你错啦！
You're wrong!
棉花鸡的精粹就是这块鱼肚
The best part of Spongy Chicken  is the fish maw
鱼肚是海棉体
Maw is spongy tissue
吸满火腿和鸡汁的精华
It absorbs all the essence  and juice from chicken and ham
要不然，怎么叫棉花鸡？
That's why it's called Spongy Chicken
小子，你说我讲得有没有道理？
Am I right, kid?
有…
I agree…
都说了不是鱼肚，是猪皮！
I've told you it's not fish maw,  it's just pig's skin
小子，你说是猪皮还是鱼肚？
Kid, do you think it's  fish maw or pig's skin?
说！
Answer me!
总之…是海棉体啦
In a word… it's spongy tissue
皆大欢喜嘛
Everybody's happy now
你无非想吸点汁
You'd better put a sponge in it
不如放块海棉下去，吸…
to absorb the juice…
吸饱了，再吃海棉吧
then you can just eat the sponge
不想跟你扯谈下去
I don't want to carry on this  nonsense argument with you
吃你的海棉体吧！
Go eat your spongy tissue!
火腿呀，猪兜！
It's your ham, pig!
吃你的海棉体吧！
Here's your spongy tissue!
我严重警告你…
干嘛？
I'm warning you…       What?
你别糟蹋我的海棉体
Don't ruin my spongy tissue
给我捡起来！
Pick it up!
是你先糟蹋我的火腿
You ruin my ham in the first place
给我吃下去！
Eat it!
还有，不准拉出来！
And don't shit it out!
棉花鸡！
Spongy Chicken!
去你的棉花鸡！
Spongy Chicken! Go to hell!
混蛋，居然打爆我的头
Damn you, you dare break my head!
无所谓，我们一起吧，你去哪？
Let's share the taxi, where are you going?
上班，九龙殡仪馆
My workplace, Kowloon Funeral Parlor
不吉利？
Think it's bad luck?
不…我很尊敬你的
Not at all… I do respect you
你不但为人民服务，还为鬼魂服务
You serve the people and the spirits too
先去九龙殡仪馆
Kowloon Funeral Parlor, please
你好，我找陈总编
Hi, I'm looking for  the Chief Editor, Mr. Chan
跟我进来
Follow me, please
你就是陆仔？     是
Are you Luk?       Yes
你是…陈总编？
Chief Editor, Mr. Chan… I presume?
你好
Hello
总“骗”辑？
Cheat Editor?
这儿有我的漫画作品
Here're all my works
当然少不了…一份故事大纲
We must have all these synopsises
我准备了中文繁体版
I've the traditional Chinese version
中文简体版
simplified Chinese version
当然也照顾了亚洲朋友的需要
I've also considered the Asian markets
有日文版
The Japanese version
韩文版
the Korean version
还有，英文版
and English version, too
预备我们将来进军好莱坞之用
So we can send it to Pixar  or Dreamworks in the near future
我看得很慢的
But I read really slow
没关系，我说得很快
No problem, I talk fast
那你说吧
Then you tell me the story
我说了     说吧
I'm going to tell the story.  Go ahead
这是一个…
This is a story…
这是一个开头亮闪闪
with a bright and shiny beginning…
后来黑压压的故事
but with a dark and eerie ending
说吧
Go on
这是一个开头亮闪闪
It's a story with a  bright and shiny beginning…
后来黑压压的故事…
but with a dark and eerie ending…
是一个关于人生无常的故事
It's a story about  the impermanence of life
所以人真的要买保险
That's why everybody should buy insurance
何太太，你先生很不幸…去世了
Mrs. Ho, unfortunately  your husband has passed away
不过很幸运
他买了我们公司的人寿保险
But fortunately he did buy  insurance from our company
但是…又很不幸…
However…unfortunately…
跟单的那位同事，就是关先生
his agent, Mr. Kwan
他上星期也…去世了
has also passed away last week
不过，现在有我负责跟进
But fortunately, I'm the one  responsible for your case now
你可以好放心啦
So you don't have to  worry about anything anymore
何太太，你先生的身故赔偿出来了
Mrs. Ho, the death benefit of  your husband has been issued
妈，是一百万呀！     是啊
Mom, it's one million.       Yes
是的，一个有计划的丈夫
即使已经去世
Exactly. A well-planned husband,  even though he is dead
也可以高度显示出人寿保险的好处
can still show the benefits  of buying a life insurance plan
令一件不幸的事没那么不幸
It makes a misfortunate event  less misfortunate
我老公一向不理会保险经纪
My husband disliked  all the insurance agents
除了关先生
except Mr. Kwan
关先生真的帮了我们大忙
Mr. Kwan has really helped us a lot
对了，关先生怎么死的？
How did Mr. Kwan die?
他是被一棵病死的树压死的
He was crushed by a collapsed sick tree
(Sick tree collapsed, crushed a man.)
所以说，人生多么无常
You see, life is so impermanent
唯一“有常”的是“人难免一死”
But there's one thing for sure,  we'll all die eventually
买了人寿保险就一定会赢
Buy insurance, you'll sure win
关先生帮我们赢了很多
Mr. Kwan really helped us a lot
好人真是死得早啊
Good men die young
像我老公，他没有朋友
Like my husband, he got no friends
每年生日只有关先生记得
Mr. Kwan was the only one  who remembered his birthday
关先生一定会寄张生日卡给我老公
and sent him birthday card every year
真的很有心…
He's so sincere…
其实关先生可以做得更好
In fact, Mr. Kwan could have  done better than this
如果他叫你先生买保额更大的保险
If he had asked your husband to buy  a plan with bigger death benefit
那你老公就死得更有价值
and make your husband's  death more worthwhile
以后我们俩就要相依为命了
The two of us have to rely on  each other from now on
母子相依为命，就更要依靠保险
That's the reason you have to  rely on insurance plan
你叫我买保险？
Are you asking me to buy insurance?
我是叫你们俩都要买保险
I am asking both of you to buy insurance
万一你有事，你儿子还有个依靠
In case there's anything happen to you,  your son can rely on that
万一他有事，你还有一张支票
Or the other way round,  you'll stilI get a cheque
所以你一定要考虑小朋友的意外人寿
Please consider the accident  and life insurance for children
现在打开报纸
多少意外都跟小朋友有关
When you read the news, you'll find  so many accidents invoIving kids
什么喝错镪水、洗发水、三聚氰铵奶
such as mistakenly drinking acid,  shampoo, melamine-contaminated milk…
打电玩打到猝死
Sudden death when playing videogames…
被门夹断手指     妈！
Losing their fingers by door…       Mom!
被摺叠卓夹爆头
Head got stuck in portable desk…
被铅笔尖刺瞎眼睛
Eye got pierced by pencil…
还有啊…
And…
被窗帘绳子勒死
strangled by windows blinds strings
所以说，人生多么无常
You see, life is so impermanent
你看，那个男人掉了张一千块钞票
Look, there's a guy  dropped his $1 ,000 note
多倒楣
How unlucky!
那个就走运啦
That other guy is lucky
他有钱捡
There's a bank note  waiting for him to pick up
你看，他连命都不要
See how he jeopardize his life just to
扑出去捡那张钞票
pick up the bank note
不过今天我们的重点是“人生无常”
But the main point today is  “Life is impermanent”
何太太，大难不死，必有开支
Mrs. Ho, there're always  expenses after a misfortune
不好意思
Excuse me
喂
Hello?
姐，今晚来我家吃团年饭吧
Sis, come over to my place for  New Year's Eve dinner tonight
好啊…不过我现在很忙
Okay… I am having a meeting now
喂…听我说完这句
Hold on… just one word
你今天有没有看？
Have you read the latest issue  of the “Super Tabloid”?
封面那个港男，我认识的
I know that macho guy on the cover page
这些等下再说吧
We'll talk about this later
你又换车？
You bought another car again?
我考虑得很清楚才买的
I bought this after contemplation
臭氧层现在都穿了个大洞了
There's a hole in the ozone layer
是吗？
Really?
这辆车很环保的
This is an environmental friendly car
那你的旧车呢？
拿去拆了
Where's your old car?  I took it to a scrap yard
那么新的车拿去拆，你还说很环保
You took a mint condition car to scrap yard?  And you say that's environmental friendly?
张太太也是开这种车的
Mrs. Cheung drives the same car
哪个张太太？
Which Mrs. Cheung?
学友的太太呀
The wife of Jackie Cheung  (famous HK singer)
车行经纪告诉我的
The salesman told me so
是吗？
Really?
喂
Hello?
你没收到我的短信吗？干嘛不回覆？
Didn't you get my text message?  Why didn't you reply?
我今晚有约会啊
I have an appointment tonight
约会？去哪里？干什么？
Appointment? Where? For what? With whom?
今晚吃团年饭
有什么比吃团年饭更重要？
New Year's Eve dinner is tonight,  what's more important than family reunion?
好啦…
Okay…
你等下传你妹妹的地址给我
Send me your sister's address
边吃边等，记住，边吃边等
Start the dinner without me.  Don't wait with empty stomach
再见
Bye
这车很静啊
The car engine is quiet
连姐夫的声音也听到
I can even hear my brother-in-law's  voice from your phone
对了，我拿了红封包给你
Right, I've brought you  some red packets envelopes
你公司的？
Gift from your insurance company?
是呀，你现在是人家的老婆啦
Now you're somebody's wife
有些事要自动自觉，做足点
You've got to initiate  and prepare everything yourself
别像以前未嫁时候
什么都要人照顾周到
Don't act if you are still single  and needed to be taken care of
我觉得…不太合适
I think… not too suitable
为什么？你不派红包吗？
Why? You're not going  to give out red packet?
我想用有我老公的姓氏的红包
I'd like to use those with  my husband's last name printed on it
你知道，我难得嫁个好老公
It's my luck to have such a good husband
跟了他的姓，他是个牙医
I have adopted his last name.  He's a dentist
有钱，又长得帅
He's rich and handsome
我不用工作，真是几生修来啊
I don't have to work at all,  feel like the luckiest woman in the world
我真要感谢上天
I really have to thank God
给我一个那么有钱的老公
for giving me such a rich husband
不要拉倒，还给我
Well, give them back to me then
我要，干嘛不要？
I want them, what makes you think I don't?
我用你的来包一百块以下的
I'll use yours to pack  those under a hundred dollars
多过一百块的…
For those over a hundred
就用我老公姓氏的红包
I'll use those with  my husband's last name printed on it
那人家也一样知道我是派大面额的
People will stilI know  I'm giving out big red packets
是吧！
Right!
不是说去你家吗？
Aren't we going to your place?
这就是我家呀，我刚刚搬来的
This is my place, I've just moved in
惊喜吧！
Surprise!
怎么样？还行吧？
How do you like it? Is this okay?
行啊！
It's okay!
好得很啊！
Very good indeed!
等等，你买了家居保险没有？
Wait, have you bought home insurance yet?
这当然要留着光顾你啦
Of course I'll buy it from you
我要孝顺姐姐嘛
It's sisterhood
要不是你供我读书
Without your support
我怎会在大学认识这个做牙医的老公
I wouldn't have met my dentist  husband in the university
其实我们一家人在这么大的房子吃饭
If our family can have  a big feast in such a big house
多开心
it'll be great
是爸爸妈妈想不通
But Mom and Dad are too stubborn
总是拿我老公跟你老公比
They like to compare  my husband with yours
老公     老婆
Honey!       Honey!
姐
Sis!
我老公今天好帅呀
My husband is so handsome today
老婆，说了生的要放下面
Honey, I've told you to put  raw food on the lower shelf
熟的放上面
and cooked food on the upper shelf
那你帮我放好吧，拜托
Will you fix it for me, please
老婆，东西弄好了，随时可以吃了
Honey, the dinner is ready,  we can start any time
等等姐夫吧     好
Let's wait for bro-in-law.       Sure
舒不舒服，老婆？
Comfy, honey?
低一点
Ah, harder
对了…就这儿
Yes… right there
你们俩搞什么？
What are you guys doing?
有长辈在，别做这个
Stop it, my elder sister is here
对了
Right
我们家的家居保险，记得给姐姐办
Remember to buy home insurance  from my sister
我今天给了病人去办
But I just bought it from my patient
好…再做一份…
Okay… I'll buy an extra one…
我现在没空接电话
I'm too busy to take your call now
如果不用覆机，请不要留言
Please don't leave any message  if no reply is needed
是爸爸妈妈想不通
Mom and Dad are too stubborn
总是拿我老公跟你老公比
They like to compare  my husband with yours
你姐怎么这么久？
Why is your sister taking so long?
我去看看
I'll check it out
姐，你没事吧？
Sis, are you okay?
快要出来啦
I'm almost done
你姐没事吧？
Is your sister okay?
我姐不开心呀
She is a bit upset
你等下出去买瓶酱油，让我跟她谈谈
You go and buy soy sauce,  let me talk to her
还说没事，这么久啊
You've been taking so long,  is there anything wrong?
老婆，酱油刚刚用完
Honey, we run out of soy sauce
你还不快去买？
Why don't you dash off to buy some?
遵命，老婆大人
Order taken, my wife commander
我去买吧，反正我也要买点东西
Let me go buy it,  I need to shop something anyway
我告诉你，记着看住我姐姐
I'm telling you, watch over my sister
我就只有一个姐姐
I only have one sister
姐，跟我过来
Sis, come with me
一辈子姐妹俩，我借我的命根子给你
We are sisters,  I'll let you use my favorite
你试拿着它出去转个圈
Try taking it with you  walking down the street
看有多少人看着你
See how many people  can't take their eyes off you
届时你的自信心肯定都回来
By then, you shall regain your confidence
不用了，我的东西都在我手袋里
No need. My stuff is in my own bag
你把东西放过来不就行了？
Just put them over here?
我都说不用了！
I said NO!
整个袋子放进去就行了
I'll put my whole bag into yours
可以了
I'm ready to go
看住我姐姐呀
Take care of my sister
是不是这个？
This one?
请让一让     对不起
Excuse me.       Sorry
那女的挺漂亮吧？
That girI is pretty?
这是你妹妹用的那种
This is the one that your sister uses
我不是说刚才那个
Not the one we just saw
我是说那天在中环看见
跟你吃午饭的那个
I mean the one that you  had lunch with in Central District
不过，我不会告诉我妹妹
But I won't tell my sister
她觉得自己活在一个美梦里
She's living in her dream
姐，你真是一个好姐姐
Sis, you're really a good sister
你也想让她继续做梦，对吧？
You wish her to keep on dreaming, right?
最要紧是别让她知道
Please don't let her know
我就不能活在美梦里了
I don't have a dream to live in
不过我也很想坐在环保豪华房车里
But I do want to sit in a luxurious  environmental friendly car
我哪有那么多闲钱呀！
I don't have that money
你帮人多剥几只牙，不就有闲钱了
You can pull more teeth from  your patients' mouths to get that money
你去把车开过来
Drive your car over there
我在前面垃圾桶等你
I'll wait for you  by the garbage bin ahead
抢东西呀…
Thief…
还不追
Why don't you catch him?
神经病呀你
You're nuts
快帮我捡回手袋
Get my bag for me
我不行，我好怕，你自己去拿吧
I can't. I'm so scared.  You go get it yourself
那手袋是你老婆的！
That's your wife's bag!
你没事吧？
Hey, are you hurt?
你的手袋也在里面呀
Your bag is inside her bag
我现在在港湾径…
I'm at the Harbour Drive…
小姐…
Miss…
手袋是我的
The bag is mine
他…抢…手袋是我的
He… he snatched my bag
是，我在…
Yes, I…
不如…你们快喝点东西定定神
Maybe you'd have a drink to calm down
谢谢老婆
Thanks, honey
姐姐
Sis
谢谢
Thanks
姐夫来啦     让我来…
Bro-in-law is here!       Let me…
喂…
Hello…
很久没见啦     你好…
Long time no see.       How are you?
新年快乐…
Happy New Year…
要不要住这么大的房子呀？
Do you need such a big house?
要的…      要吧？
It's necessary…        Necessary?
要不要脱鞋子？
Do I need to take off my shoes?
无所谓，随你喜欢吧
Never mind
过来坐…
Have a seat…
胖子
Fatty
怎样，姐夫？
What's up, bro-in-law?
这部很贵呀
That's expensive
姐夫识货，这套东西是挺贵的
You are knowledgeable,  it's quite an expensive one
有没有夏韶声、蔡琴的唱片？
Do you have Danny Summer's  and Cai Qin's CDs?
菜就有得吃
Dinner Winter and Cuisine  are available now
来呀，过来吃饭吧
Come on, dinner is ready
咬文嚼字，好样的…
You sure know how to do wordplay, bravo…
妹妹，好久不见了
Sis, long time no see
瞧你的头，至少要弄三小时
Look at your hairdo, you have taken  at least 3 hours to set it
像个贵妇一样
Just like a noble lady
贵妇呀
Noble lady
老婆
Honey
打了好几次
I phoned you a couple of times
不接电话，去哪呀你？
You didn't answer your phone,  where have you been?
亲一下
A little kiss
浑身酒气，又去跳舞？
You drank at the nightclub again?
姐夫，坐吧
Bro-in-law, have a seat
难得我们一家人
We don't have family reunion everyday
在我老公买的这个大房子里…
In such a big house of my husband…
当然要开开心心吃团年饭嘛
Let's enjoy our New Year Eve's dinner
对了，姐夫，先混酱吧
Bro-in-law, mix the sauce first
好啊
Okay
老婆，我帮你混
Honey, let me do that for you
我最知道你喜欢啥，不喜欢啥
I know what you do like  and what you don't
你明知我不喜欢，还去跳舞？
You know I don't like you going  to nightclub, why you go there?
姐，我帮你烫你最喜欢
吃的芝士肠和芝士丸
Sis, let me cook some cheese sausages  and cheese balls for you
芝士肠好肥呀，芝士丸也很肥的
Cheese sausages are fatty,  and so are cheese balls
老婆，你也很胖呀
Honey, you're fat
老婆，有的人胖就好看点
Honey, some people look nicer  with some extra pounds
有的人瘦好看，我就觉得你胖好看
while some people look nicer when slim.  I think you look nice when you're fat
所以多吃点，尽量吃，相信我别怕
Just eat as much as you can,  don't worry. Trust me
姐夫！
Bro-in-law!
不如我烫点肥牛肉给你吧
Let me cook some fatty beef for you
老婆，又肥又老呀
Honey, so fat and so old
你闭嘴！
Shut up!
不用理他，我们吃
Never mind him, let's eat
我们吃吧
Let's eat
我到这儿不是来吃你耳光的
I don't come here to be slapped
你们夫妻俩耍花枪，别放在心上
You guys are just flirting,  don't take it too hard
不放在心上，放哪里？
Can I pretend I haven't been slapped?
放芝士丸里面好吗？
Or I have been hit by a cheese ball?
其实我已经饿极了
Actually I'm starving
不如大家先吃吧，好不好？
Shall we start dinner?
一句话，如果她不向我道歉
If she doesn't apologize
我现在立刻走！
I will leave
我立刻就走！
I am leaving now
为什么我要向你道歉？
Why should I apologize to you?
我刚才跟一帮少女
喝酒跳舞，开心得很
I sacrifice the fun of  hanging out with pretty chicks
现在跟你们这帮老东西在这磨时间
just come here to be with you old guys…
我都不计较了
That's fine with me
没错，我喝酒跳舞是不对
Right, I did drink and dance
你也不用在你妹妹
和妹夫面前落我面子
But you don't have to disgrace me  in front of your family
我最讨厌就是你
明知我不喜欢，还去跳舞
Despite you know how I hate  those nightclubs, you still patronize them
你也明知我不喜欢跟你家人一起吃饭
Despite you know how I hate  dining with your family
可我还是来了
I'm still here
我家人有什么问题？
What's wrong with my family?
是你自己跟我说你妹妹和妹夫…
It's you who told me  your sis and her husband…
你搞什么呀…
What's wrong with you…
你打我姐！
You hit my sis?
姐，你怎样？
打女人不是男人所为
Sis, are you okay?  Shame on you for hitting a woman
痛吗？
那我就打男人，站住
Does it hurt?  Then I'll hit a man. Stand still!
老公，你怎样？
Honey, are you okay?
你打我老公！
You hit my husband?
不好意思，我…
Sorry, I…
够啦！
That's enough!
我还手啦…
I am gonna fight back…
你看你，搞得人家不得安宁，混蛋！
Look at you, you just  messed that all up, bastard
最坏是你这个臭婆娘！
You are the one to be blamed on
混蛋！
Bastard!
你把东西扔向我？你吃错菜啦！
What the hell! Are you nuts?
你欺负我姐姐…
Dare you bully my sis…
不知好歹的东西！
You shameless punk!
你别过来…我捅死你！
Don't come over… I'll stab you
怕了吧…我掐死你呀！
Scared?… I'll strangle you to death!
我最恨人用芝士肠扔我的头！
I hate being hit in the head by sausages
我掐死你…
I'll strangle you to death…
你住手！
Stop that!
还不帮忙
Aren't you gonna help?
你干嘛插我腋窝？
Why did you stab my armpit?
打我姐姐…
You hit my sis…
你滚开呀…
You get lost…
你干嘛插我腋窝？
Why did you stab my armpit?
够啦…你干嘛…
Stop that…
勒索我？
Blackmail me!
环保车！
Environmental friendly car!
老婆！     干什么？
Honey!       What is it?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
你想泼我？
You wanna attack me with hot water?
你心知肚明
You'd know what you have done
你干嘛要泼我姐？
Why did you attack my sis?
是她先勒索我
She blackmailed me first
你干嘛勒索我老公？
Why did you blackmail my husband?
他在外面有女人呀，你还蒙在鼓里
He has other woman, he cheated on you
你在外面干嘛有女人呀？
Why did you do that?
是不是我不够好？
Am I not good enough?
你疼音响多过疼我
You loved your Hi-Fi better than me
你不是人！
You are scum!
你才不是人！
You are scum too!
搞我老婆…
Dare you hurt my wife…
我老实告诉你
Let me tell you
我平时已经在人家面前做足戏
I used to play a good husband  in front of your family
给足你面子了
to give you honour
我今天还在你姐、你姐夫…
I even pretended to enjoy
在这种跑龙套的闲人面前做足戏
the companion of your sis and her husband
你还想我怎样？
What else do you want from me?
你说什么？
What did you say?
你知不知道自己在说什么？
Do you know what you are talking about?
我当然知道我说什么
Of course I do
我倒过来再说一次也行呀，臭婆娘！
I can say that again,  even in reverse, bitch
你骂我臭婆娘，那你还娶我？
You called me a bitch,  why did you marry me then?
是你骗我娶你的
You cheated me and made me marry you
结婚前，你说自己多么贤淑
Before we got married, you told me  how virtuous you would be
结婚后，我才知道你挥霍无度
Afterwards, all you do  is spending extravagantly
一天都晚就是买车买车
You just keen on buying cars
为了你，我少买了多少套喇叭！
Do you know how many Hi-Fi speakers  I have given up because of you?
结婚时，你爸爸妈妈谋我
When we get married,  your parents wanted my money
结了婚…你谋我
After that, you want my money
现在我想离婚，连你姐也来谋我
Now I want a divorce,  your sister wants my money
全家都是贼，都是贼…
You are all thieves…
都是贼！
Thieves!
贼！
臭嘴巴…
What a nasty mouth…
吃死你呀！
You eat now!
骂我爸爸！
Dare you call my dad a thief?
骂我妈妈！
Dare you call my mom a thief?
骂…
Damn…
看你还骂…
Dare you say that…
都是贼…
Thieves…
老婆，我再不去医院…
Honey, I'll be gone…
我真的会完蛋了
if I don't go to the hospital in time
好痛…      对不起，老公
It hurts so much…       Sorry, honey
好痛啊     马上去医院
It hurts.       Go to hospital now
别动筷子…
Don't touch the chopsticks…
等我，姐姐！
Sis, wait for me
赢了一场架，输掉一个家
Won the fight but lost the family
妹夫悔不当初，一个人在房子坐
Bro-in-law sat alone  in the house with remorse
这故事…可不可以有人死？
Could someone die in this story?
行…你想要谁死？
Okay… which one you want dead?
总之找个人死，商业点嘛
Whoever, just trying to be commercial
这个嘛…
Well…
不如…
How about…
(Fighting at the year end dinner)  (in a disharmony family.)
这个结局是不是较商业化呢？
This sounds more commercial?
总之，越多人死就越商业化
Higher the death toll,  the more commercial
行…要我死也行
Sure… I could die too if you want
我跟大老板谈谈，再通知你
I'll talk to my boss, I'll let you know
谢谢…
Thanks…
什么来的？
What is it?
999报案中心
999 emergency report center
员警，救命…
Police, help…
很高…有人扔东西下来…
Someone threw bottles of  liquid… from above…
是腐蚀性液体…溅中好多人
It's corrosive liquid…  many people got hurt…
一滩滩…满地一滩滩…
It splashed all over, it's everywhere…
先生，请问你现在位置哪里？
Where's you location?
IFC
IFC in Kwun Tong?
不是中环，是观塘
Not in Central, in Kwun Tong
观塘IFC？
Kwun Tong IFC?
先生，知不知道打电话
来报案中心开玩笑
Do you know you'll be charged
你会被控报假案的
for making false reporting
还有，999报案中心的
电话是用来救命
999 report center is for  people who are badly in need
不是用来玩的
It's not for prank call
我不是开玩笑
I'm not kidding
我是见义勇为，我是良好市民呀
I'm just trying to be a good citizen
我六岁就加入“少年警讯”啦
I've joined Junior Police since I was six
我把每集都录下来
I recorded every episode of  “Junior Police” (TV program)
你现在诬蔑我报假案？
Now you're trying to  defame me for false reporting?
又不是我受伤，也不是我家人受伤
Neither me nor my family got hurt
我肯抽时间来报警…
I still take time to report this…
妹妹，借个电话
Miss, can I borrow your phone?
那边不就有电话了？
Isn't there a phone?
先生…借个电话我报警
Sir, can I borrow your phone  to call the police?
我正在跟报案中心说话呢
I'm now talking to them right now
我现在让伤者直接跟你说
I will let the victim  talk to you directly
喂，是不是员警？
Hello? Is it the police?
先生，谢谢
Thanks, sir
谢谢你
Thanks
救护车快到了
The ambulance will be here soon
不用客气…
You're welcome…
再见
Bye
你不陪我等员警呀？
Aren't you staying with me  till the police arrive?
你是男人，不用陪了
You're a big man,  no need for companionship
那你也要录口供呀
You have to give your testimony too
这么麻烦？
So troublesome?
用你的电话报警，一查就知道了
I used your phone, they can trace back
别走啊！     我不知道…
Don't go!       Don't ask me…
我什么都不知道呀
I know nothing about this
喂     麻烦你陆仔
Hello?       Is it Luk?
你是谁？
Who is it?
我是玲玲，小学同学
It's Ling Ling,  Luk's primary schooI classmate
玲玲，你真幸运
It's you, Ling Ling! You're so lucky
你迟十秒打来，我就接不到你的电话
I won't be able to answer your call  if you call me 10 sec later
你没事吧？     没事…
Are you okay?       Okay…
那就记得今晚来喝喜酒
Then come to my wedding banquet tonight
多年没见，我结婚，你没藉口不来吧
We haven't met for years,  you have no excuse for not coming
你来看我有没有嫁错老公嘛
Please come to check out my Mr. Right
行…一定来
Okay… I will come
我现在化妆，不跟你说了
I need to dress-up now, I got to go
今晚见     好，今晚见
See you tonight.       Ok, see you tonight
立即注销这个电话号码
Cancel this phone number
在单子上写明
Write this down…
我的电话已经丢失
I've already lost my phone
搞定了，这部是新电话
It's done. This is the new phone
电话卡在里面了
The sim card is inside
你新的电话号码…记住了
This is your new phone number… remember
64897123
一小时后可以用了
The service will commence after one hour
要一个小时？
An hour later?
能不能借个电话？
Can I borrow your phone?
有新电话当然要先通知女朋友
I should tell my girIfriend  about the new number
我有女朋友了
I already have a girIfriend
我现在没空，方便的话请留言
I'm not available at the moment,  please leave your message
喂，朱…朱莉亚
Hello? Ju… Julia?
没什么，刚换了一部新电话
Nothing special, I just got a new phone
打算跟你…
I want to tell you…
留言信箱已满
This voice mail box is full
谢谢
Thanks
单据
Here's your receipt
师傅劳驾，九龙城鸳鸯酒楼
Excuse me, please go to Kowloon City,  Yin Yang restaurant
喂，陈总编辑
Hello? Mr. Chan
是，我是陆仔呀
Yes, I'm Luk
对，我还在等你的消息
Yeah, I'm still waiting for your call
想跟你说一声，我丢了电话
I just want to let you know  that I've lost my phone
现在新电话号码是
6489…7123
My new phone number is 6489…7123
对…
Yes…
等会儿我再用短讯发一次给你
I'll text you my new phone number
麻烦了，谢谢
Thank you
今天下午四时左右，在观塘区
This afternoon around  4 o'clock in Kwun Tong
有人从高空掷下腐蚀性液体
someone threw corrosive liquid  from a building
在场有二十多名路人被溅中
More than 20 people were injured
警方现正在现场一带大厦
进行逐家逐户调查
The police is now investigating  the buildings in the area
暂时未拘捕任可人
No suspect has been arrested yet
警方呼吁知情市民
打举报热线87654321
The police is now calling on witnesses  to phone the hotline 87654321
此外，在这宗案件当中…
Besides, in this case…
一名被硬物击中头部的男伤者
there's a victim who  was hit by a hard object
不幸被赶至现场的救护车撞倒
unfortunately got run over  by an ambulance
卷入车底，当场死亡
He's pronounced dead at the scene
今晨，九龙城一家茶楼发生凶杀案
There's a homicide case  in Kowloon City this morning
两名男子因为一碟棉花鸡引起争执
Two men's quarrel over Spongy Chicken  led to a fatal fight
其中一名男子被人
用硬物重击头部至死
One of them got killed by a hard object
警方现正扣留一名男子协助调查
A suspect has been detained by the police  for further investigation
(Argument over a dish of Spongy Chicken)  (turned into a fight!)
不是吧，这样也行？
What the hell! Is that true?
师傅，我在这儿下车吧
Excuse me, I'm getting off here
好的
Okay
谢谢五十八元
$58, thanks
六十元，不用找
Here's $60, keep the change
谢谢
Thanks
按什么喇叭，赶着去死呀？
Come on, what are you rushing for?
干嘛拍我的车？
Why did you slam on my car?
我问你是不是赶着去死！
I'm asking you if you are rushing to hell!
是不是赶着去死呀！
Are you rushing to hell?
(Two drivers fought over cutting in line.)
小朋友
Hey, kid
你抽烟就算了，当街看色情书也算了
If you want to smoke and watch  pornography, that's fine with me
拜托先脱下校服吧
but please don't wear your schooI uniform
关你屁事
It's none of your business
老公！     喂
Honey!       Hi!
喂…
Hey…
你们打呗儿就算了
You guys want to kiss in public place,  that's fine with me
可别当众摸她胸部嘛，大哥
but come on, please don't hold her breast
这是街上呀
Here is a public area
关你屁事
It's none of your business
喂，行…我现在上来
很重啊
请大家再靠近一点，对，谢谢…
Everybody get closer, right, thanks…
不好意思，这两位
Excuse me, you two
刚好挡住，麻烦你们站出来
You just blocked them, please stand out
不…站进去
No… go inside
录影来的，要有动感
It's a video, give me some motion
喊开拍时你们才走出来，好不好？
As I say “action”,  then you guys walk out, okay?
麻烦你，站这儿
我不跟他站一起
You, stand here.  I'm not standing with him
小姐，你不跟他站一起是吗？
Miss, you're not standing with him?  That's fine
喊开拍你才走
Just walk away from him  when I say “action”
前面那排可以先站起来
The front roll could stand up first
对，一二三开机大家才坐下
Right, sit down after I count to three
开拍
Action!
走吧
Motion
摆什么酒，劳民伤财
Wedding banquet, my ass
新郎说，来宾要蟹柳杯面就可以任点
The bridegroom said,  only cup noodle could be ordered
要蟹肉伊面就说卖光了
But not for crabmeat noodle
没钱就别结婚
Shit! Shouldn't hold any  wedding banquet if you are broke
有空上东莞，搂搂北妹，喝喝啤酒
Go to Dongguan hanging out with chicks
天天娶老婆，你说多开心呀
would be happier
没关系…再来一次
It doesn't matter… Take Two
再斟一杯
One more
你说他们能好多久？
You guess how long they will last?
我找高人算过了
I've found a prophet to predict that
他们不出七七四十九天就会离婚
They will divorce in 49 days
哪位高人？     姓高，名仁
Which prophet?       Mr. Profit
(Chan & Lee's Wedding)
这个又不跟那个坐，怎么办？
They don't want to sit at the same table,  how could I arrange then?
不如叫他们坐主家席吧
Just tell them go sit at the head table
有人来，欢迎     欢迎
Here comes a guest. Welcome!       Welcome!
我是新娘的小学同学
I was the classmate of the bride
请签名…
Please autograph…
小学同学，九号卓
Table 9 for primary schooI  classmate, please
一点心意，给这对新人
This is for the bride and groom
停…
Cut…
不好意思，大哥，刚才来不及开机
Sorry, the camera was not rolling
请你再来一次，谢谢
Please do it again
开拍
Action!
一点心意，给这对新人
This is for the bride and groom
请说几句恭贺话
Please say something nice  to the newly-weds
祝你们…
Wish you guys…
年年有今日
happily ever after
岁岁有今朝
Till death do you guys apart
臭小子！刚才只顾着玩
叫你尿也不尿
Brat! You just care to play  and won't go to washroom
不憋到最后一刻，你都不作声
You hold your pee till the last minute,  then you give me the ultimatum
不如像上次那样
Son, do it like last time
我不尿在洗手盘里
I don't want to pee in the sink
为什么…
Why…
为什么不是我！
Why it's not me?
恭喜…      谢谢…
Congratulations…        Thanks
我是你老婆的小学同学陆仔
I'm your wife's primary schooI classmate,  my name is Luk
谢谢赏面…要多喝点
Thanks for coming
继续说，当我不存在，自然点
Keep talking as if  I am not here, be natural
你真行呀，真是…
You are great…
我以前想请你老婆喝维他奶
I did have a crush on your wife  when we were little
我想了六年都没行动
but I didn't have a chance
这么惨啊？     你真行
What a pity!       You are the winner
对了，你老婆呢？
Right, where's your wife?
她说累了…
She said she's tired…
要换衣服，还要换妆
and she's got to change and make-up
欢迎…
Welcome…
男家还是女家？
Bride's side or bridegroom's side?
我是新郎的前度女友
算男家还是女家？
I'm the bridegroom's ex-girIfriend,  so what do you think?
新郎哥！
The bridegroom!
真要恭喜你呀
Congratulations
麻烦你先拍我妈妈那边…
Please shoot my mother first…
谢谢
Thanks
你说不来，怎么会在这儿？
I thought you won't come,  why are you here now?
是不是很惊喜？
So are you surprised?
你忘了？你说过要娶我的
Did you forget that  you promised to marry me
不如…先打几圈麻将吧
How about playing mahjong
我知道我少了什么
I know what I'm short of
小姐，请问穿几号尺码？
Miss, what's your size?
36D
P0
你是说D…还是C？
Did you say D or C?
你快去拿G号给这位小姐
Get a G cup for this lady
G？     对
G?       Right
其实戴G号，加些配套就更好
But G-cup has to go with some accessories
你看这边
Look at these
海棉j仔糕，价钱便宜一点
Spongy bra pad, it's economical
夏天来说，我觉得会比较热
but they're too thick  for the sweaty summer
所以有些客人会多花点钱
Some customers would prefer these
不怕贵的，买这个
regardless of the price
矽胶     是什么呀？
Silicon gel.       What are those?
矽袋，用来隆胸的
Silicon gel, same material  for breast implants
你摸摸
Touch it
真的很有手感
It feels so genuine
是啊，穿汗衫、衬衫的话
Yeah, if you wear T-shirt or blouse
可以用这个，满月型
you can use the “full moon” pads
如果是开领的话
If you wear strapless
可以用这个，半月型
you can use the “half moon” pads
如果是低V，可以用这个新月型
If you wear deep-V,  you can use the “new moon” pads
现在做宣传推广
During the promotion period
如果你买一盒，三种款式全有了
you can buy the combo,  all 3 types of pads in one box set
适合你任何场所、任何日子
You can wear them in any occasions
以及任何人的评头品足
to meet the challenge of being  judged by any kind of people
保证所有自信心全回来
Satisfaction guarantee.  Regain your confidence
打个八八折给你
Give you a 12% off discount
全都包起来！
I'll take the combo
你有没有觉得，我今天有什么不同？
Do I look different today?
妆很浓
You're heavy make-up
再往下看
Look downward
介绍我朋友给你认识
Let me introduce my friend to you
陆仔
Luk
玛丽艾塔
Marietta
一场相识…两人打麻将吧
You two should play mahjong
两人怎么打麻将呀？
Mahjong can't be played  byjust two persons
兄弟…
Buddy…
一个人没得玩呀
You can't play alone
我找了两个牌脚给你
I've found someone  to play mahjong with you
我马上给你找一个
I'lI get one more for you
不用了
No need
可乐，还不过来跟我打？
Rocky, will you accept my challenge?
怕再输给我呀？
Worry about losing to me again?
说什么呀六宝？怕你？
What did you say, Luk Po?  You think I'm afraid of you?
对了，各位从事哪个行业？
By the way, what business are you guys in?
跟打麻将有什么关系？
Why? Is it related to mahjong?
小弟是搞艺术的
I'm in contemporary art
也挺喜欢跟各路英雄打打交道
I like to meet with people  from alI walks of life
我做导游
I'm a tourist guide
香港九龙…
Hong Kong Kowloon…
我们喜欢香港…
We loved Hong Kong…
我教跳舞
I'm a dance teacher
乖脚趾…
Good toes…
坏脚趾…
Naughty toes…
摘这花…
Pluck this flower…
采那星…
Pick that star…
我是护士，在整容诊所工作
I'm a nurse in a plastic surgery clinic
我好害怕
I'm so scared
不用怕，这种肉毒杆菌针很多人打过
Don't be scared, many people  have tried “botox” before
不是，我是怕外面的狗仔队
No, I'm scared of  those paparazzi waiting outside
等会儿我怎么出去？
How could I leave here?
张太太，你放心，我有办法
Mrs. Cheung, don't be afraid.  I have an idea
先躺下，打支针
Just lie down, get the shot
真的认不出来？
Are you sure they can't recognize me?
你戴上这假发就认不出来了，我帮你
As long as you put on this wig,  let me help you
保证认不出来
No one could recognize you
我带你走后门
I'll take you out from the back door
你的工作挺偏的
Yourjob is kind of unique
是不是看到很多人性弱点？
So you have seen the  weakness of human nature?
这是我的名片
This is my name card
我换了电话
I've just changed my phone number
这是新电话
This is the new number
有空出来喝喝茶
Let's meet some other time
刺激一下我的创作灵感也好呀
So you can tell me  some inspirational stories
谁打骰子？     我
Who's gonna throw the dice?       Me
到你摸牌
Your turn
干嘛？找朋友？
What's the matter? Looking for friends?
不…新娘换衣服很久了
No… the bride has taken  so long to get changed
都没看见我的小学同学
I haven't seen any of  my primary schooI's classmates
小学同学？都已经变样啦
Primary schooI's classmates?  They might have changed so much
不会那么容易认啊
How could you recognize them?
自摸双辣！
Win on “self-draw”, it is “one suit”
这么快自摸？说不定是骗子出千
So soon? Are you cheating?
你说什么？
What did you say?
什么！就是你一向用的阴招
What? You used to play sly trick
安吉莉娜宝贝就是这样被你撬走的
That's how you stole  Angelina Baby from me
你说，你亲我的时候是不是想着她？
Tell me, are you thinking of her  when you kiss me?
哪个她呀？
Who's “her”?
你干嘛？
What's wrong?
六宝说，你整天躲在厕所看她
Luk Po said you enjoy watching her  photo-collection in the washroom
这本书不是我的
This book's not mine
安吉莉娜宝贝！
Angelina Baby!
六宝！
Luk Po!
多嘴问一下
I'd like to ask…
谁是安吉莉娜宝贝？
Who's Angelina Baby?
就是撬走我新郎哥的那个！
The one that took away my bridegroom
彼得
Peter
你是不是娶我？
Will you marry me?
有样东西给你
I have something for you
你连喜帖都印好啦？
You even got our  wedding invitation card ready?
亲亲
Kiss
安吉莉娜与彼得？
Angelina and Peter?
你跟那个婆娘结婚？
You're gonna marry that bitch?
怎么会这样？
Why?
没办法，她…有了
I've no choice, she's pregnant
你不是说她打掉了吗？
Didn't you say she has  gone through an abortion?
是，但是…
Yes, but…
又有了
She's pregnant again
怎么会这样？你个混蛋！
How could it be possible? You bastard!
你们的关系真是错综复杂
You guys have such a  complicated and messy relationship
不是虚线，就是实线
Just like entangling lines  in a relationship chart
小姐，这是表面上假好心
Miss, that's pretentious
实情是害你
In fact they're trying to harm you
你说什么？
What did you say?
打牌搭人家肩膀呀
Tapping on someone's shoulder  when playing mahjong is bad luck
东西可以乱拍，话可不能乱讲
You should watch your mouth
虽然你我素昧平生
AIthough it's the first time we meet
但我能够体会你的伤感
I do understand how sorrowful you are
因为小弟今早也被女朋友抛弃了
My girIfriend has dumped me this morning
这里有包纸巾，希望能帮你
Here's tissue paper, hope it'll help
带纸巾外出的男生真的很体贴
A guy that brings tissue paper along  must be tender-loving-care
你女朋友不识货
It's your girIfriend's loss
你女朋友错失良机
Your girIfriend missed a Mr. Right
喂
Hello?
你那边踩场踩成怎样？
How are you doing in the wedding banquet?
我还没看见那婆娘
I haven't seen that bitch yet
现在踩到麻将卓上了
I'm now playing mahjong
说回你那笔…
Regarding you…
我有个很细心的好男生介绍给你
I do have a tender-loving-care  guy for you
你等等
Wait
不会吧…
No way…
他不要，让给我
He passes, give it to me
他害羞啊
He's too shy
我回头传他的电话号码给你
I'll text you his phone number later
他是个…
He is…
带纸巾，够细心，大好青年
a tender-loving-care young man  who brings along tissue paper
你耍我呀？
Don't try to fooI me!
不跟你说了，我要打麻将减压
I'm hanging up, I need to play mahjong  to relieve my stress
再见…
Bye…
(A tender-loving-care young man who brings)  (along tissue paper. Phone number: 64897123.)
六对半！一双一对，真扎眼
6 pairs and a half! Suck! All in pairs
那就做对对糊吧？
Go for “all pong hand” then?
你是挪移还是挖苦？
我偏不做对对糊！
Are you teasing me?  I won't go for“ all pong hand” though
有种你就拆散它们吧
Dare you break them up
拆散你！     碰！
Break you up!       Pong!
拆散你！     碰！南！
Break you up!       Pong! “South”!
你不是吧？
Are you kidding?
在我人生最悲伤的时候
你叫大四喜？
It's the saddest time in my life；  you are ready to claim for “big 4 winds”?
你是不是串通他们一起来耍我？
Are you guys trying to set me up?
没这种事…
Of course not…
塘边鹤，他是不是做大四喜？
Bystander, is he claiming  for “big 4 winds”?
是不是？
Isn't it?
你们问我已经很不对了
It's not right for you to ask me
我再回答，不就更错？
And it'll be wrong for me to answer you
这位兄弟，等会儿…
Buddy, wait…
如果有人打番子出来，你喊糊的话
If someone discards an honour tile  and you're claiming for a win
记得要喊大声点，清楚点
then you have to  declare it loud and clear
看这儿，记住要笑
And, look at the camera,  remember to smile
笑呀
Smile
别想了，拆了就拆吧
Don't think about that,  just break them up
拆散你！
你怎么这么多事？
Break you up!       Are you that nosy?
拆啦
Break them up
是你打还是她打？
请问谁打呢？
Who's playing now?  May I know who is playing now?
我打！拆散你！
I'm playing! Break you up!
再拆吧
Again
拆散你！
Break them up!
现在是你打还是她打呀？…
Who's playing now? You or she?…
六筒
“6 stones”
我不拆啦！
I'm not gonna break these two up
七筒     吃！
“7 stones”!       “Hu”! (Winning)
吃回七筒这么狡猾？
You're so cunning to have  a “ready hand” for a “7 stones”
我出冲了？
Huh? I have to pay double?
还好，鸡糊来的
It's lucky that it's  just a “chicken hand”
你错啦，这里一台花，加一张正花
You're wrong, here's a  “all flowers” and a “seat season”
三番
Three “fans”. (points)
又输啦！
Lost again
我的纸巾给你用光了
You used up my tissues
或者，要不要离开这个伤心地？
Should you leave such a grieving place?
是啊，你还留在这儿干嘛？
Yeah, why should you stay here?
何必让人在你的伤口上洒盐呢
Shouldn't let people  sow salt on your wound
我来这里做事的
I'm here to “work”
做什么？
What?
你关掉摄影机，我告诉你们
You switched that off and I'll tell you
好，我不拍
Okay, already off
知不知道这瓶是什么？
Do you know what this is?
什么来的？
What?
肉毒杆菌
Botulinus
名字这么毒？
What an awful name!
也就是Botox
That's Botox
是整容诊所帮人瘦面去皱纹用的
It's used in plastic surgery clinic  for wrinkle elimination
就是你打的那种？
You have tried that?
差不多
Kind of
不过，这瓶是经过提炼
But this one's been refined
高纯度的肉毒杆菌
It's highly concentrated
要是吃进肚子里
绝对可以杀人于无形
It could kill if taken orally
不过我现在烦恼着
应该把它放在第几道菜
I'm wondering in which dish  I should put this
才不会伤及小朋友
so that no children will be hurt
以我的经验
小朋友吃完鱼翅就到处跑
According to my experience, children run  around after having the shark's fins
你不可以这样做！
You can't do that!
为什么？
Why?
让我来
Let me do it
知不知道这瓶是什么？
Do you know what this is?
可乐呗     当然不是
Coke.       Of course not
这瓶可乐昨晚已经被我喝光了
I drank the coke last night
这经典的可乐瓶子里面
Now, it's highly  concentrated flammable liquid
装的是高度易燃液体
inside this classic coke bottle
这么厉害？
So cooI
有没有学名？
Is there any technical name for that?
你懂个屁！化学你都不及格
You know shit about that!  You failed your chemistry though
你只会勾人家的女人！
You just know luring other's girIfriend
安吉莉娜宝贝呀！
Angelina Baby!
待会你们找个安全地方躲一躲
When the time comes, you guys better  find a safe place to hide
你呀，要把我拍得好看点
You must take good shot of me
我会…
I will…
谢谢各位来宾赏面出席
Thanks for coming to our banquet
大家干杯！
Cheers!
各位来宾，我的宝贝！
Ladies and gentlemen,  I loved Angelina Baby!
我不是泼你冷水
I'm not trying to discourage you
但我觉得你很蠢
But I think you're so stupid
我把你拍得多帅也没用，你都看不到
You wouldn't be able to see it  even I've taken good shot of you
他一直是这样，思想只有幼稚园程度
He's always like this,  he's just up to kindergarten level
看看我吧
Watch me
希望大家今晚多喝一杯！
Hope you will enjoy the dinner. Cheers!
好，我们祝贺这对新人！
Okay, let's greet on the newlyweds
恭喜…
Congratulations…
先生女士们，小朋友和大人
Ladies and Gentlemen…
我们一起欣赏这对新人的浪漫史
Let's share the romantic  story of the couple
放片！
Here it goes!
怎么不是新郎？
It's not the groom?
宝贝…
Angelina Baby…
正点
Great!
你们俩待会什么都别做
You two, don't do anything
我玛丽艾塔要做的事，谁也阻挡不了
No one can stop what  Marietta is going to do
你这样活活杀光了观众
If you kill all my audience
没有人看我殉情了
no one can see me  being the martyr of loved
你那个光害人，你那个光害自己
Your way will only harm the others  while yours will only harm yourself
我这个又害人又害己
Mine will do both
当然首选我这个杀伤力最强的
My way is most harmful. Use mine
大哥，你快说句公道话
Bro, you should say something
你，搞生化战，涂炭生灵
You are deploying biochemical lethal stuff,  plunging people into abyss of misery
你傻兮兮，自找苦吃
You are such a fooI,  kicking yourself against the pricks
最坏是你
You are so evil
非法强迫他人分享你的淫亵影片
You force others to  share your obscene clip
缺德老套，天怒人怨！
Wicked, tacky and indignant
摄影师哥哥，请问…
Bro, I'd like to ask…
你口袋里那支笔怎么会有灯亮着？
Why is your pen having a light?
你偷拍？     你偷拍我们？
You…  You are taking sneaky shot on us?
偷拍？     放手…
Taking sneaky shot?       Let me go…
我有你们三个的犯罪证据
I got the proof of you guys' crime
你们三个的下场都会一样
You guys wilI have the same ending
仆…
Damn…
你有种再仆一次？
Dare you say that again?
我不仆啦
I'm not
我…
I fxxk you all fxxking bastards
你…      我让你仆！
You…       Damn you!
太失礼了！
Too shameful!
什么事？
What's happening?
上面是拍电影还是着火了？
Is it on show or on fire up there?
是不是砍人呀？
Is someone got chopped up?
麻烦让让…      陆仔…
Give way…       Luk…
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是玲玲呀，你怎么从上面下来？
I'm Ling Ling.  Why are you coming from up there?
(Chan & Lee's Wedding)
我不知道…
I don't know…
上面发生什么事？
恭喜了…
What happened up there?  Congratulations…
早生贵子！
Hope you'll give birth soon
我现在正忙，请留下口讯
I am busy right now,  please leave a message
朱莉亚！
Julia!
朱莉亚，是我呀
Julia, it's me
不知道为何今天这么背
走到哪都遇上坏事
I don't know why I'm so pissed today,  all the bad things are coming to me
我可能开始倒楣了
I must be out of luck
其实你走得真是时候
You left at good timing
我不想连累你
I don't want you to  get invoIved in my bad luck
总之，祝你幸福
Anyway, all the best
朱莉亚     喂…
Julia?       Hello…
陈总编
Oh, Mr. Chan
你马上来“危情夜总会”
Come to “Against All Odds Club” now
夜总会？     卡拉OK呀
Club?       Karaoke
是卡拉OK还是夜总会呀？
It's karaoke or club?
是“危情卡拉OK夜总会”
行了吗？
It's “Against All Odds Karaoke Club”, okay?
老板在等你呀
Boss is waiting for you here
马上来…
Okay, I'll be right there
(A man was killed in a)  (wedding banquet conflict.)
老板，我最近很失落
Boss, I've been so down lately
妈妈病了，妹妹又要交学费
My mom is sick,  I've to pay for my sis' tuition fee
昨天，有个老板说要包我三个月
Yesterday, a boss asked me  to be his mistress for 3 months
但是，我最舍不得是你
But I miss you so much
所以还在考虑
So I'm still thinking about that…
等会儿你就跟你的客人说
Then you'd tell your other clients  that you've been so down lately
你很失落，妈妈病了
妹妹没钱交学费
your mom is sick and you've to  pay for your sis' tuition fee
昨天有个老板说要包你三个月
Yesterday, a boss asked you  to be his mistress for 3 months
但你最舍不得他
But you miss him so much
所以还在考虑，明白吗？
And you're still thinking  about that, okay?
好不好听？
How's that?
叫大声一点嘛，拍手
Louder! Clap hands!
大声一点…老板唱得好！
Louder! Boss, you sing so well
老板，是这边呀
Boss is over there
怎样，有没有听我唱歌？
What's up? Did you listen to my singing?
过儿哥，你唱得很好听
Don Guo, you sang so well
当然好听     好听啊
It's good though.       It's nice
闪开…
Piss off…
老板…
Boss…
怎样？
他就是那个画画的
What's it?       He's the cartoonist
老板，你好！
Hi, boss
你就是画画的？
You are the cartoonist?
样子长得挺卡通
Your look is funny though
今晚想怎样醉？
How would you like to get drunk tonight?
白兰地、红酒、女人、大麻
Brandy, red wine, women, cannabis…
什么都有，任君选择
We've everything here
老板问你想怎样醉呀
Boss is asking how  you would like to get drunk
老板…这样…
Boss… well…
听完故事才醉，行不行？
May I tell the story before I get drunk?
行，陈仔
Okay, Punk
学着吧，这就叫专业
you should learn this,  that's what we call professional
倒杯酒给他
Give him a drink
还不谢谢老板
Shouldn't you thank boss?
喝吧！     谢谢…
Drink up.       Thanks…
老板，不介意的话，我就开始了
Boss, I'd like to start now
说吧…
Go ahead…
这故事是一个本来不应该死人
In this story,  there shouldn't be anyone die…
但最后死了很多人的故事
but so many people died at the end
这故事，一个开头亮闪闪
It's a story with  a bright and shiny beginning
后来就黑压压的
and with a dark and eerie ending
这故事讲述四种人
This story tells 4 kinds of people
第一种，以为自己很幸福
First kind, those who  think they are being well
其实是糊里糊涂
but in fact they are just too befuddled
第二种，幸福，因为他糊里糊涂
Second kind, they are being well  because they are befuddled
第三种…
Third kind…
身在福中…不知福
they fail to appreciate that  they have been being well
第四种，他不知道自己
是幸福还是不幸福
Lastly, they don't know whether  they are being well or not
因为他从没去想
because they've never thought of that
说完了
The End
好笑吧？
Funny?
好不好笑？
Is it funny?
好笑吧？
Funny?
行不行？
Is that good?
行，很好呢
Good, it's very good
好！明天上班！
Okay, get on to work tomorrow
把你的故事写成漫画
Make your story into comics
再拍卡通片都可以，是吧？
Or even cartoon movie will do, right?
还不谢谢老板
Shouldn't you say thanks to your boss?
喝吧     喝！
Drink it.        Drink up!
干…
Cheers…
干！
Cheers!
看清楚嘛！
Be careful!
喂，朱莉亚
Hello? Julia
我好开心啊…
I'm so happy…
是的…我可以出书啦！
Yes… I'm gonna have my own comic
喂，你干嘛不说话？
Hello? Why don't you say something?
干嘛不…理我？
Why don't you care about me?
你不高兴呀？
Are you upset?
但是我现在兴奋极了…
But I'm so excited now…
可以出书啦！
I'm gonna have my own comic
其实我不是很开心
In fact I'm so upset
因为我不可以没有你
because I can't live without you
对不起
Sorry, man
他刚才坐过儿哥那张台的
He just sat with Don Guo
幸会…
Nice meeting you…
龙女姐…
Donna Dragon…
还不叫龙女姐
Say hello to Donna Dragon
龙女姐…
Hi, Donna Dragon…
你们也叫声过儿哥
You guys should say hello to Don Guo too
过儿哥…
Hi, Don Guo…
闪开     自己找位子坐
Get lost!       Go, take a seat
来，喝一杯
Come on, have a drink
你的？     是
Yours?       Yes
你的花柳好了吗？
Has your venereal disease healed?
好了…哪有呀！
Yes… No, I never had that!
你是想吵架？
Are you asking for a fight?
我现在…还在找你偷的那个汉子
I'm… still finding who your Cicisbeo is
都说没有了
I don't have one
没有？那当初还赶我出家门口？
If not? Why did you  kick me out of our home?
说了一千次，我更年期嘛
I told you a thousand times,  I was going through menopause
藉口
Just an excuse
这么多年了，都没跟人那个呢
I haven't done that with  anyone for so many years
今晚我要跟你…
Tonight, I want to do it with you…
猜几拳！
to have finger-guessing game!
喝！
Drink!
嗨
Hi
这烟是你的？
Your cigarettes?
整包拿去吧
Take the whole pack
刚才…谢谢了     谢什么？
Just now… thanks.       For what?
你夸赞我的故事
You praised my story
是好的话，我就会说好
I say it's good because it's good
以后我的故事会有个角色…
Someday I will name a character
用你的名字
after you
你知道我叫什么名字？
You know my name?
方美芳
Fong May Fong
我有话要跟你说
I've something to tell you
能不能找个安静的地方？
Can we find a quiet place for that?
我只是想找个安静的地方谈谈
I just want to find a quiet place to talk
我真的只想谈谈
I just want to have a talk
你想说什么？
What are you trying to say?
本来是有话想说，但是…
I do have something to say, but…
还没想到重点
I can't think of the main point
那你怎么写书呀？
How could you be a writer?
因为我分了心
I could if I'm not distracted
现在我想到啦
Now I got it
你吃了什么药，这么可爱？
What drug did you take? You're so cute?
方美芳，别在这里做
Fong, don't do it here
那你想在哪里做？
Where do you want then?
不…你误会了…
No… don't get me wrong…
我意思是叫你别在这儿上班
I mean, don't work here anymore
那你有没有钱？
Do you have money then?
没有
No
你没钱，我不会跟你的
You've no money, I wouldn't be your girI
不如我说个故事给你听
Then let me tell you a story
什么故事？
What story?
从前，有个卖火柴的女孩
Once upon a time,  there's a little match girI
不是…是一个公主
No… should be a princess
但是她不知道自己是公主
But she doesn't know her true identity
这个公主上学读书
This princess goes to a bad schooI
同学全都是来自五湖四海
Her classmates are from alI walks of life
三山五岳，没有一个好人
None of them are good stuff
那些老师…也懒得理
The teachers there just won't give a damn
最有勇气的，就是提醒你交学费
What they care most is not the students,  but the tuition fee
公主很彷徨
The princess is so lost and miserable
很想找人帮助，但没有人帮助她
Hoping someone may help her,  but her hope is in vain
直到有一天
Until one day
她遇到一个王子
she's met a prince
这王子很好，什么都肯给她
The prince is so nice  and willing to give her everything
所以，公主也什么都肯给王子
So the princess is willing to  give whatever the prince wants
但是，有一天…
But, one day…
王子变成了青蛙
the prince turns into a frog
而公主就变成…援助交际
While the princess  turns to compensated-dating
不好意思，我不是援助交际
Excuse me, I'm not  into compensated-dating
我是性工作者
I'm a sex-worker
那我希望性工作者最后一夜上班
Then I do wish that…the sex worker
明天做回公主
will turn back into a princess tomorrow
凭什么要我听你的？
What makes you think I'll listen to you?
我的心
My heart
我想，这个愿望也不算过分
I guess, my wish is not that demanding
那你有没有过分的愿望？
Do you have demanding wishes?
有
Yes
抽完这包烟，戒掉它吧
I'd like you to quit smoking  after this pack
你是不是耍花样？
Are you trying to mess with me?
想干嘛？
What do you want?
想劈你呀！
I will chop you up!
还有人     你什么态度啊?
It's occupied.  What kind of attitude is this?
还有人…
Someone's still inside…
总编！
Mr. Chan
你慢慢…我回去开工啦
Take your time… I'm going back to work
那你想怎样？
What do you want then?
什么想怎样？
What do you mean?
这么多年来，你都没说让我
It's been so many years,  you've never given in to me once
我不让你，你还能站在这？
If I don't give in,  would you be standing here alive?
话不要反过来说，反骨仔
You, traitor,  shouldn't say the other way round
今天我就跟你算清这笔帐！
I'm gonna settle this with you
还不知道谁欠谁呢
Don't know who owes who
进房里算！     走啊！
Let's talk about that inside.  Let's go
弟兄们
Buddy!
今天我过儿哥有事要公告天下
Don Guo has something to announce
多年来，我爱龙女姐爱得好痛苦
I've been loving Donna Dragon  for so many years
今天龙女姐终于答应我，再嫁给我
Today, Donna Dragon finally  promised to re-marry me
明天我和她举行婚礼！
We wilI have the  wedding ceremony tomorrow
干嘛要等到明天？今晚吧
Why tomorrow? Tonight's still young
好！
Okay!
从今晚开始，你老大就是我老大
Starting from tonight,  your boss is my boss
我老大就是你老大
My boss is your boss
大家就是兄弟姐妹啦
We are brothers and sisters then
我们两位老大水乳交融
Our bosses are having  a good time together
我们做小的，当然要欢乐今宵！
We small potatoes should  also enjoy ourselves
一时失志不免怨叹
It'd be frustrated
一时落魄不免胆寒
during the bad times
那通失去希望
Losing all the hope
每日醉茫茫
and fooling around
无魂有体亲像稻草人
Just like a dead man walking
人生可比是海上的波浪
Life is like the waves in the sea
有时起有时落
There would be ups and downs
好运，歹运
Good luck or bad luck
总嘛要照起工来行
You stilI have to live everyday anyway
三分天注定，七分靠打拼
30% depends on fate,  70% depends on effort
爱拼才会赢
You've to fight in order to win
(A tender-loving-care young man who brings)  (along tissue paper. Phone number: 64897123.)
喂…
Hello…
朱莉亚，你终于肯打给我啦
Julia? You finally called me
喂…
Hello…
这故事…可不可以有人死呀？
Could someone die in your story?
所以说，人生多么无常
That's why we say, life is impermanent
是不是赶着去死！
Are you rushing to hell?
喂
Hello?
(Fireworks in nightclub)  (caused devastating fire.)
吃饭啦
The meal is ready
一分钟
Give me one minute
但是我想这个世界美好一点
But I'd like a better world
那你自己美个够吧
You just go ahead then
我把它留下来
你交给能拿主意的人看
I'll leave them here,  you take this to someone who have say
棉花鸡     来一笼…
Spongy Chicken.       One please…
还是不要了
Well… no thanks
没有了，就这些
There's nothing else, just these
留给别人吧
Leave that to others
棉花鸡
Spongy Chicken
干嘛敲我的车？
Why did you slam on my car?
我问你是不是赶着去死！
I am asking you, are you rushing to hell?
哥，我老婆生啦！
Bro, my wife is gonna give birth
一分钟，我只是在干活
一分钟马上走
Give me one minute. We're just earning  our livings. I'll leave in one minute
恭喜…
Congratulations
成家了     谢谢赏面，请坐
I'm married.  Thanks for coming, have a seat
婆婆，看这边     陆仔
Granny, look here.       Luk!
玲玲
Ling Ling?
你瘦得…我差点认不出来了
You are so slim that  I can't recognize you
恭喜…      谢谢…
Congratulations…        Thanks…
新郎呢？     他在楼下那层
Where's the groom?       He's downstairs
这里不是“陈李联婚”吗？
Isn't here Chan & Lee's Wedding?
今天巧得很，三层都是“陈李联婚”
It's such a coincidence, all three floors  are booked by “Chan & Lee's wedding”
那你…
Then why are you here?
楼下厕所多人，我只好上来一下
The washroom downstairs is packed,  so I try this floor
快走…
Let's go…
喂     喂，陆仔
Hello?       Luk?
我是陈总编，正在跟老板唱卡拉OK
I'm Mr. Chan, I'm in karaoke with boss
别说我不给你机会
Don't say that I won't give you a chance
再问你一次，你的故事肯不肯死人？
Will someone die in your story?
我还是想这个世界美好一点
I do want a better world
方美芳
Fong May Fong
我认识你吗？
Do I know you?
你掉了学生证
You dropped your student ID
是你的     谢谢
It's yours.       Thanks
我很喜欢你的校服
I like your schooI uniform
别误会，我以前也在这所学校读书
Don't get me wrong,  I'm an old boy of your schooI
以前会考，我有两优四良
I did have 2A's and 4B's in HKCEE
原来学校的传说是真的
So the legend is true
很多事是靠自己的
One has to be self-reliant
你也要努力，别荒废了自己
Try your best, don't waste yourself
朱莉亚
Julia?
怎么今天没有人死？
Why is there no one died today?